(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
アイドルに笑顔なんて要らない。
Idols don't need smiles.
そんな世界は要らない。
I don't need such a world.
アイドルに笑顔なんて要らない。そんな世界は要らない。
Idols don't need smiles. I don't need such a world.
違法なアイドルライブ！？
An illegal idol live!?
アイドルに笑顔はいらない！
Idols don't need smiles!
さあ、聴いてください！
Now, please listen!
誇り高きアイドル！
Proud Idol!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
私のこと知ってますか？
Do you know about me?
可愛く見えてますか？
Do I look cute to you?
私の歌、どうだろうな
I wonder how my singing is
上手く歌えてますか？
Am I singing well?
衣装だとかメイクだとか
Like my outfit or my makeup
可愛く見えてますか？
Do I look cute to you?
振り付けだとか演出とかも
My choreography and the stage effects too
喜んでもらえますか？
Will they make you happy?
手が冷たくなって
My hands are getting cold
足が震える
and my legs are trembling.
それでも戦いたい
Still, I want to fight
アイドルだから
because I'm an idol.
泣き虫な奴は嫌いだ
I hate crybabies
…だされるのも嫌いだ
...I hate being belittled.
貶されるのも嫌いだ
I hate being belittled.
アイドルなんかという言葉を
The word "idol" and such,
見てもいないくせに言うな
Don't say it when you haven't even seen me.
頑張り屋通せというな
Don't tell me to be a hard worker.
イメージを決めつけるな
Don't force an image on me.
アイドルなんかという言葉は
The word "idol" and such,
この世で一番大嫌いだ
Is what I hate most in this world.
プライベート見えないから
Because you can't see my private life,
わからないと思います
I don't think you'd understand.
生活とか悪い方です
My lifestyle and such is on the bad side.
騙しちゃっていますか？
Am I deceiving you?
でも本気です 本気なんです
But I'm serious, I really am.
ありのままの私も
The me just as I am,
好きになって推してください
Please come to like me and support me.
それってわがままですか？
Is that being selfish?
綺麗事じゃない
It's not just pretty words.
全部わかってる
I know everything.
それでも好かれてたい
Even so, I want to be liked.
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol.
批判する奴は嫌いだ
I hate those who criticize me.
表面ばかりも嫌いだ
I hate superficiality too.
こんなもんかという言葉を
The words "Is this it?",
軽々しく口にするな
Don't say them so lightly.
勝手に限界決めるな
Don't decide my limits on your own.
笑いものになんてするな
Don't make me a laughingstock.
アイドルなんかという言葉は
The word "idol" and such,
この世で一番大嫌いだ
Is what I hate most in this world.
向かい風を切り裂け
Cut through the headwind.
誇り高きアイドル
A proud idol.
目指そうぜ
Let's aim for it.
応援がなければ勝てない
Without support, I can't win.
凄い奴に感化されてはいけない
I mustn't be influenced by the great ones.
手に入れるはずが貰ってばかりだし
I was supposed to gain things, but I'm just receiving them,
恩返しできる日まで待ってて！
So please wait until the day I can repay you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
歓声が減っても
Even if the cheers decrease,
飽きられちゃっても
Even if people get bored of me,
それでも笑っていたい
I still want to be smiling,
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol.
熱いファンの愛があって
With the passionate love of the fans,
スタッフさんの愛があって
With the love of the staff,
いつも家族の愛があって
With the love of my family always there,
生きてる、上がれ！
I'm living, so rise up!
馬鹿にする奴は嫌いだ
I hate those who make fun of me.
貶されるのも嫌いだ
I hate being belittled too.
アイドルなんかという言葉を
The word "idol" and such,
見てもいないくせに言うな
Don't say it when you haven't even seen me.
頑張り屋通せというな
Don't tell me to be a hard worker.
イメージを決めつけるな
Don't force an image on me.
アイドルなんかという言葉は
The word "idol" and such,
この世で一番大嫌いだ
Is what I hate most in this world.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
え？
Eh?
なになにこれ？
What, what is this?
大空警察さーん！
Ozora Police!
こっちです！
Over here!
こちらで違法なアイドルライブが行われてます！
An illegal idol live is being held here!
なに？
What?
大空警察です！
It's the Ozora Police!
アイドルが公の場で笑顔を振りまく行為は禁止だ！
It is forbidden for idols to scatter smiles in public!
今すぐ解散しなさい！
Disperse immediately!
さっ、早く！
Now, hurry!
ちょっと、どういうこと？
Wait, what do you mean?
解散って...
Disperse...?
違法なアイドルライブって...
Illegal idol live...?
いやいや、アイドルが違法ってどういうこと！？
No, no, what do you mean by idols being illegal!?
そんなの聞いてないよー！
I haven't heard of such a thing!
とにかく逃げなきゃ！
Anyway, I have to run!
舞台「尾丸ポルカ」～あゝ素晴らしきアイドル人生かな～
尾丸ポルカ 2周年記念公演
Stage "Omaru Polka" ~Ah, What a Splendid Idol Life~
Omaru Polka 2nd Anniversary Commemorative Performance
ようやく逃げてこれられた...
I finally managed to escape...
なに？なんなの？
What? What was that?
違法なアイドルライブとか言ってたっけ？
Did she say "illegal idol live"?
いや、しかも、大空警察さんまで来てたし...
No, and even the Ozora Police showed up...
えー！？
Eeeeek!?
これからどうなっちゃうの？
What's going to happen to me now?
アイドルライブ…できるのかな？
Will I be able to... do an idol live?
でもアイドルはそんなことしないとか、違法とか言ってたし…
But they said idols don't do those things, and that it's illegal...
えー！？やだ！
Eh!? No way!
私まだいっぱい歌いたい歌あるし、
I still have so many songs I want to sing,
アイドルライブやりたいし！
and I want to do idol lives!
それに…
Besides...
ファンの子たちにだっていっぱい想い届けたいから。
Because I want to deliver so many feelings to the fans too.
そんなのおかしいじゃん。
That's just wrong.
レーザーガール
作詞/作曲:sasanomaly
Laser Girl
Lyrics/Composition: sasanomaly
あのね私ルーザーガール
You know, I'm a loser girl
だって開き直るしかないじゃん
Because I have no choice but to be defiant
レッテル貼られて悪くはない
Being labeled isn't so bad
仕方がないけど今までは
It can't be helped, but until now...
負けられないのよ
I can't afford to lose
ここで勝たなきゃもう人生一生止まって
If I don't win here, my life will stop forever
じゃあ私にできることは何
So, what is it that I can do?
さあ私にできることは何
Come on, what is it that I can do?
誰か教えて それじゃダメなのと
Someone tell me, will I struggle forever
一生もがんだか
knowing it's no good?
あの子みたいになりたくて
I wanted to be like that girl
あの子みたいになれなくて
But I couldn't be like her
楽しくて 満たされて
Until it ends with being fun, being fulfilled,
もういいやって終わるまで
and saying "I'm done"
最初ってそんなもんで
That's how it is at first
自分に言い聞かせて
I keep telling myself
でもいっそ 足りなくて
But rather, it's not enough,
もういいやって止まれない
and I can't stop even if I say "I'm done"
気づいた時私は
By the time I realized,
何者かになりたくて
I wanted to become someone
だんだん周りが見えてきたんだ
Gradually I started to see my surroundings,
ライバルが立ち並んで
with rivals standing all around
だんだん私の立場も見えて
Gradually I saw my own position,
大したことないな
and realized it's nothing much
レッテル貼られて悪くはない
Being labeled isn't so bad
スパイスなんだけど今までは
It was a spice, but until now...
言いたいだけなのよ
I just want to say it
ここで勝たなきゃもう人生一生止まって
If I don't win here, my life will stop forever
じゃあ私にできることは何
So, what is it that I can do?
さあ私にできることは何
Come on, what is it that I can do?
努力したけど それじゃダメなのと
I made an effort, but will I struggle forever
一生もがんだか
knowing it's no good?
あの子みたいになりたくて
I wanted to be like that girl
あの子みたいになれなくて
But I couldn't be like her
どんどん周りと距離が離れて
More and more the distance from others grows,
ライバルですらなくて
I'm not even a rival
どんどん私の足元崩れて
More and more the ground beneath my feet crumbles,
このまま落ちようか
shall I just fall?
あのね私ルーザーガール
You know, I'm a loser girl
待って置いていかないでよなんて
Wait, don't leave me behind, or something like that
あのね私ルーザーガール
You know, I'm a loser girl
だって開き直るしかないじゃん
Because I have no choice but to be defiant
レッテル貼られて悪くはない
Being labeled isn't so bad
仕方がないけど今までは
It can't be helped, but until now...
生き抜くためなのよ
It's for the sake of surviving
ここで見せなきゃもう人生一生止まって
If I don't show it here, my life will stop forever
じゃあ私にできることは何
So, what is it that I can do?
さあ私にできることは何
Come on, what is it that I can do?
誰か教えて それじゃダメなのと
Someone tell me, will I struggle forever
一生もがんだか
knowing it's no good?
努力したけど それじゃダメなのと
I made an effort, but will I struggle forever
一生もがんだか
knowing it's no good?
あの子みたいになりたくて
I wanted to be like that girl
あの子みたいになれなくて
But I couldn't be like her
この世界のトップアイドルとの出会い
Meeting with the top idols of this world
ひよこの声がしたのは、こっちの方かな？
Did Hiyoko's voice come from this way?
なんかすごい盛り上がってたけど、
It seemed really lively,
もしかして、アイドルライブ？
could it be an idol live?
あ！
Ah!
あれ？
Wait?
やっぱり！アイドルライブじゃん！
I knew it! It is an idol live!
ねぇ、なんでそんな笑ってないの？
Hey, why aren't you guys smiling?
え？やっぱりさ、おかしいよね？違法なアイドルライブなんて。
Eh? It really is strange, right? An illegal idol live.
今のアイドルってどうなっちゃったの？
What's happened to idols nowadays?
ねぇ、もっとキラキラしてるアイドルに、
Hey, I want to become a more sparkling idol,
ポルカ、もう一回なりたいよ！
Polka wants to become one again!
どうすればいいの？
What should I do?
ダメなのだよ。
It's no good.
え？
Eh?
アイドルは笑顔なんて見せないのら。
Idols don't show smiles.
そんな…
No way...
アイドルはみんなの手の届かない、
Idols are beings out of everyone's reach,
神聖で素晴らしいもの。
sacred and wonderful.
あなたもこうなりたいなら、頑張るしかないね。
If you want to be like this too, you'll just have to do your best.
え？いやいや、やっぱりそんなのおかしいって。
Eh? No, no, that's definitely wrong.
それに、ファンの皆はそもそも…
And besides, the fans in the first place...
そんなこと...
Something like that...
望んでるのかな?
I wonder if they want that?
おっ...
Oh...
あっ、座員くん!
Ah, Zain-kun!
え、ちょっと待って!
Wait, hold on!
座員くん!
Zain-kun!
待って、ねえ!
Wait, hey!
君、座員くんだよね?
You're Zain-kun, right?
あ、あれ?
Huh?
どっか行っちゃった。
He went somewhere.
あれ...私、どうしたんだっけ?
Wait... what happened to me?
ここ、どこだっけ?
Where am I?
あれ? ああ、分かんないや。
Wait? Oh, I don't know.
アリーナなのに、
Even though it's an arena,
アリーナみたいじゃない。そんな気がするし。
it doesn't feel like one. At least that's how it feels.
座員くんも夢?
Was Zain-kun a dream too?
何が正しいの?
What is the right thing?
アイドルって何?
What is an idol?
笑うことがアイドルじゃないの?
Isn't being an idol about smiling?
アイドルって、笑わせて、笑ってもらって、
An idol makes people laugh, gets laughed at,
笑顔を振りまいてさ。
and spreads smiles around.
そうじゃないんだ、今は。もう...
That's not how it is now. Enough already...
そっか。
I see.
こんな世界、おかしいよ!
This world is just wrong!
全部壊れちゃえばいいのに。
I wish everything would just break.
Hello! Hello! Everyone まもなく On Stage
Hello! Hello! Everyone, almost On Stage
Lie Life 自己暗示 さあ 始めよう
Lie Life, auto-suggestion; now, let's begin
「ようこそ Party Night」 誰かが騙る
Someone falsely claims, "Welcome to Party Night"
連日満員御礼 どうぞ最贔屓に
House full every day; please, show your favoritism
「待ってた Show Time」 誰かが騙る
Someone falsely claims, "The Show Time you've been waiting for"
どうでもいいような顔を見せてよ
Show me a face that doesn't matter
ハブ、ご乱心、炎上
Hub, losing one's mind, flaming
並べた嘘、一子相伝
Lined up lies, secret succession
ふざけちゃいませんか?
Aren't we just fooling around?
今辿り着いた憧れの世界
The world of my dreams that I've finally reached
ここはまるでペテン師の楽園
This place is just like a swindler's paradise
吐き気を飲み込む
Swallowing down the nausea
前座、幕が開けた オノマトペ
The opening act, the curtain rises; onomatopoeia
群がる人形はダリアの花束を
The swarming dolls carry bouquets of dahlias
本日、大団円 脚本が笑う
Today is the grand finale; the script is laughing
騙されていてくれる貴方達と
With all of you who are willing to be deceived
アタシ今ここで何をしてる?
What am I doing here right now?
耳をつんざく 拍手喝采
Deafening applause and cheers
サルもおだてればヒトにもなれる
Even a monkey can become human if flattered enough
フォーカスされた日常
A focused-upon daily life
引き金を引いて真実を射抜くように
Like pulling the trigger to pierce through the truth
一回、二回、三回、嘘を重ねて
Once, twice, three times, piling up the lies
十回、千回、億回、瞳を逸らして
Ten, a thousand, a hundred million times, averting my eyes
あれ? アタシは誰かな? アタシは...
Wait, who am I? I am...
アタシは誰?
Who am I?
もうウンザリした仮面舞踏会
I'm sick of this masquerade ball
とりとめもないワルツでお出迎え
Greeting you with a rambling waltz
贋作の中 おどけてみせてよ
In this forgery, put on a funny show for me
嘲ってみせてよ
Show me your ridicule
アタシの世界は ぐるぐるぐるぐる 廻っていく
My world goes 'round and 'round and 'round
前座、幕が開けた オノマトペ
The opening act, the curtain rises; onomatopoeia
群がる人形はダリアの花束を
The swarming dolls carry bouquets of dahlias
選んでくれた服を着て踊りましょう
Let's dance in the clothes you picked out for me
騙されていてくれる貴方達と
With all of you who are willing to be deceived
いいよ、もう。これが好きだっただけだろ?
Fine, whatever. This is all you liked, isn't it?
振り落とせ ペルソナを
Shake off the persona
とっくに終わった 喜劇は悲劇と化してなお
Long since finished, the comedy turns into tragedy and yet
(今日も普通に楽しかったよ)
(I had a normal amount of fun today too)
さあ刮目してくれよ
Now, keep your eyes peeled
本当の僕は アタシじゃないから
Because the real me isn't 'her'
(今日も普通に楽しかったよ)
(Today was also fun as usual.)
全力　幕が上がる　空想のオノマトペ
All out, the curtain rises. A fictional onomatopoeia.
着せ替え人形と　輪廻のアンコール
A dress-up doll and a samsara encore.
本日　大団円　客本位のお笑い
Today, the grand finale. Customer-centric comedy.
どうしようもないよな！？
It's helpless, right?!
あぁ、
Ah,
どこの誰でもいい　「調子に乗るなよ」と　ただ一回言ってくれ
I don't care who it is. Just tell me "Don't get ahead of yourself" just once.
そういやユングも散々言ってたな
Come to think of it, Jung kept saying it over and over.
「もう後戻りは叶わない」と
That "There's no turning back now."
気付けばそこは独りきり
Before I knew it, I was all alone there.
どうせフィクションの物語
Anyway, it's a fictional story.
そ、どうせフィクションの物語だからね。
Right, because it's just a fictional story anyway.
そう、フィクションだけに...
Right, because it's fiction...
...フィクション（ハクション）って！
...'Fiction' (Achoo)!
あはは、あはは。
Ahaha, ahaha.
ははっ、またおまる変なことしてる。
Haha, Omaru's doing weird things again.
ラミィ！
Lamy!
はいはい、また遊びに行こうね。
Yeah yeah, let's go out together again.
お、う、ありがとう。ラミィだけだよそんなの。
Oh, uh, thanks. Only you'd say that, Lamy.
え？
Eh?
こよりはポルカ先輩のこと、大好きですよ！
Koyori loves you, Polka-senpai!
もっと自信持って！一緒にアイドル活動続けましょう！
Have more confidence! Let's continue our idol activities together!
お、わかった。
Oh, I get it.
二人がそう言ってくれるなら、私もうちょっと頑張れるかも。
If you two say so, I might be able to work a bit harder.
よし、
Alright,
私は頑張って
I'll do my best
変えていく、この世界を！
to change this world!
決意
Determination
エヴァーブルー
Ever Blue
作詞/作曲 ぬゆり
Lyrics/Composition by nulut
太陽が地平線に飲み込まれるのを眺めていた
I was watching the sun being swallowed by the horizon.
まぶたを閉じれば
If I close my eyelids,
わたしも消えてしまえるような気がしたのに
I felt as if I could disappear too, and yet...
くだらない白昼夢に終止符を打つ
Putting a full stop to the pointless daydream,
生活の着信音
the ringtone of daily life.
馬鹿になった蛇口
A broken faucet,
節制のない心　鏡は曇っている
an intemperate heart. The mirror is clouded.
脱ぎ捨てた靴さえよそよそしい
Even the shoes I kicked off seem distant.
ここは底なしの海を
This is a bottomless sea.
悲しくはない
I'm not sad.
苦しくもない
I'm not in pain.
寂しくもない
I'm not lonely.
悲しくない　苦しくない
I'm not sad, I'm not in pain,
寂しくない　悲しくない　苦しくない　寂しくない
I'm not lonely, I'm not sad, I'm not in pain, I'm not lonely.
あぁもううるさいな
Ah, enough already.
うおぉぉ
Whoa...
どこまでも沈む
Sinking forever.
神さまでさえ見つけられないくらい
So deep that even God can't find me.
深く深く深く沈んでいく
Sinking deeper, deeper, deeper.
なまぬるいバスタブ
A lukewarm bathtub.
乾いたタイルに響くレクイエム
A requiem echoing on dry tiles.
せかいがわたしだけを置いていく
The world is leaving only me behind.
泡になってなくなってしまうなんて
Becoming bubbles and vanishing...
美しい終わりはきっと来ない
such a beautiful ending will surely never come.
魂ひとつすらままならないし
I can't even manage a single soul,
せかいは不完全で果てがないもの
and the world is incomplete and boundless.
連れて張り付いた孤独が冷え切って
The clinging loneliness has chilled to the bone,
いつまでもわたしをがんじがらめにしている
and it keeps me bound hand and foot forever.
この薄暗い部屋にたたずんで
Standing still in this dimly lit room,
永遠の終わらせ方を知らないまま
without ever knowing how to end eternity.
狙いでは夜光虫
By design, noctiluca.
水面は遠く　静寂と赤信号
The surface is far away. Silence and a red light.
ハイでショートしている　帰れないどこも
Shorted out while on a high. There's nowhere left to go back to.
揺らぎ続けている
Continuing to waver
さあ 時間だ
Now, it's time
かじかんだ身体が離れていく
My numbed body is drifting away
なにも感じたくない もう
I don't want to feel anything anymore
うお お お どこまでも落ちる
Whoa, falling forever
朝焼けでさえ照らしきれないように
So that even the sunrise cannot fully illuminate
昏く昏く溺れていく
Drowning deeper and deeper into the darkness
なまぬるい冷徹
Lukewarm cold-heartedness
1ドル銀貨の月さえ見放す
Even the one-dollar silver coin moon abandons me
エヴァーブルー 染まっては続くフューネラル
Ever Blue, the funeral continues as it's dyed
乾いた夜更けに燃えるレクイエム
A requiem burning in the parched late night
せかいがわたしだけを置いていく
The world is leaving me behind
そして、革命
And then, revolution
皆さん、
Everyone,
私が今期のトップアイドルに選ばれました、
I have been chosen as this season's top idol,
尾丸ポルカと申します。
I am Omaru Polka.
私がこの座に選ばれたからには、
Now that I have been chosen for this position,
この現状の腐ったアイドルをぶっ壊し、
I will destroy these currently rotten idols,
新しくぴかぴかと輝いたアイドル、取り戻したるかんな！
And I'll bring back a brand new, sparkling idol!
行くぞ！ついて来いよ！
Let's go! Follow me!
もうステージは始まってんだぜ！
The stage has already begun!
おりゃあ、行くぞ！
Alright, here we go!
これがアイドルだ！
This is what an idol is!
最強なポルカになる。
I'm becoming the strongest Polka.
サイキョウチックポルカ、
Saikyou Tick Polka,
お前ら見とけよ！
You guys, watch me!
アクセスようこそ
Welcome to the access
朝昼夜もなく
No matter morning, noon, or night
会いに来てくれてうれしい
I'm happy you came to see me
わたしも実は待ってた
Actually, I was waiting too
今日のあれこれ
Today's this and that
キミと共有して
Sharing with you
おかえりも行ってきますも
Both 'welcome back' and 'I'm off'
自由な時代だもん
It's a free era, after all
主張強めだった？
Was I too assertive?
意識高めだった？
Was I too high-conscious?
お天気次第とか言えない言い訳より
Rather than excuses like "it depends on the weather"
たのしい至上主義
The supremacy of fun
極めていきたい
I want to master it
ご賛同ありがとう
Thank you for your support
これがわたしの流儀
This is my style
カンチガイされたら
If I'm misunderstood
そりゃまーヘコむよ
Well, of course, I'd feel down
キミのことが好きだし
Because I like you
ペチャンコポルカから
From flattened Polka
歩み寄ってハニカム
I'll step closer and shyly smile
ちょっとしたご意向
Just a small intention
ハートレベルアップしちゃう
My heart level is going up
ムテキなポルカ
Invincible Polka
サイキョウチックポルカ
Saikyou Tick Polka
こういう距離感
This kind of distance
今時ほしいのか
Is it what's wanted nowadays?
家族とか友達よりも
Closer than family or friends
近く感じることあるし
Sometimes feeling that closeness
急にご無沙汰するときがあっても
Even if I'm suddenly out of touch for a while
いつだって戻ってこれた
You could always come back
遊び場っていいよね
Playgrounds are nice, aren't they?
一過性って言わないで
Don't call it temporary
永遠って聞かないで
Don't ask for eternity
自分たち次第未来も変えられる
Depending on us, we can even change the future
たのしい至上主義
The supremacy of fun
極めていくから
Because I'm going to master it
ご協力ありがとう
Thank you for your cooperation
モニター越しのサーカス
A circus through the monitor
よろこんでくれたら
If you're pleased
そりゃめちゃアガるよ
Well, I'll be super hyped
キミのことが大好きだもん
Because I love you so much
トビダスポルカ
Fly out, Polka!
ハイになって確信
Getting high and feeling sure
紛れもない想い
Unmistakable feelings
レベル無限アップしちゃう
My level is going up infinitely
ムテキポルカ
Invincible Polka
サイキョウチックポルカ
Saikyouchic Polka
Welcome!
やっぱりこれじゃないとポルカじゃないよね！
It wouldn't be Polka without this outfit!
本当の本当にお待たせしました！
I really, really kept you waiting!
アイデアかわいい　笑顔がいのち
Cute ideas, smiles are life
笑顔を世界中に最強に広げちゃえ
Spread smiles across the world to the max!
みんなで笑って
Everyone, laugh together
It's Show Time!
これから何が見たい？
What do you want to see now?
どんな時でもついてきてね
Follow me at all times
私は座長 尾丸ポルカ
I'm the ringmaster, Omaru Polka
あ、もう名前は覚えてくれてるかな？
Ah, have you already remembered my name?
本当の本当にありがとう！
Thank you so, so much!
準備は出来てますか？
Are you ready?
Are You Ready?
さぁさぁ 違うにおいで きっと誰もが病みつき
Come, come, with a different scent
Everyone's sure to get addicted
奇想天外 ショーの始まりさ
An extraordinary show is about to begin
さぁ ぐっと惹かれるでしょう ほら お早めに
Now, you'll be strongly drawn in
Look, hurry up
それでは準備OKですか？
So, are you ready?
愉快な動物たち 玉乗りピエロ
Cheerful animals, ball-balancing clowns
ハラハラドキドキしちゃうんでしょう
It'll make your heart pound, won't it?
綱渡りして
Tightrope walking
衝撃的なドジなんて怖くないよ
I'm not afraid of shocking blunders
Come on! Light up!
とっておきのライブ
A special live performance
ぼーっとしてないで もっともっと 踊り明かそう
Don't just stand there
Let's dance more and more through the night
ほらほら ついておいで
Hey, hey, follow me
目が回るような サーカス きっとここだけの魔法
A dizzying circus, surely a magic only found here
ホログラムみたい キラキラ奇跡が踊る
Like a hologram, sparkling miracles dance
驚かせちゃう
I'll surprise you
世界中を虜にしちゃうぞ
I'll captivate the whole world!
うーん 今日の演目はどうしようかな
Hmm, what should today's program be?
屋根裏で秘密の作戦会議から始めるか
Shall we start with a secret strategy
meeting in the attic?
このいっぱいの観客席をわっと驚くような
To wow this packed audience
とびきりのショーを見せましょう
Let's show them an extraordinary show
思い付いたら じっとしてらんない
Once I think of it, I can't stay still
座員を引き連れて Let's Go
Leading the troupe, Let's Go!
あれがやりたい！ これもやりたい！
I want to do that! I want to do this too!
どうして時間って足りないの？
Why isn't there enough time?
ポルカおるか！
Is Polka here?!
コールお願いします！
Please do the call!
ポルカおるか！
Is Polka here?!
手拍子してもいいよ！
You can clap along too!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
ポルカおるか ポルカおるか ポルカどおるか
Polka is here, Polka is here, how is Polka doing?
ポルカおるか ポルカおるか ポルカここに居るよ！
Polka is here, Polka is here, Polka is right here!
強く強く願うんだ
I wish strongly, so strongly
どんな夢だって きっときっと 叶うはず
Any kind of dream will surely, surely come true
何も怖くない
I'm not afraid of anything
みんなの声は全部ちゃんと届いてるよ
Everyone's voices are all reaching me properly
さあ 新しい自演
Now, a new performance
新しい舞台へもっと さあ もっと 突き進もう
Toward a new stage, let's push forward even more
まだまだ付いておいで 笑わせちゃうから
Keep following me, I'll make you laugh
さあ 絶対ここだけだよ
Now, it's definitely only here
初めての仲間
My first companions
楽しい君 ここで共に踊る
Joyful you, dancing together right here
今にも世界中を
Any moment now, all over the world
虜にしちゃうから
I'll have everyone captivated
目を離しちゃダメだぞ
You mustn't take your eyes off me
離さないでね
Don't let go, okay?
私の思うアイドル、見つけたよ。
I found the idol I envision.
舞台「尾丸ポルカ」〜あゝ素晴らしきアイドル人生かな〜
Stage "Omaru Polka" ~Ah, what a wonderful idol life~
Fin.
月の光が
The moonlight
映し出したエピローグ
Reflected the epilogue
屋根裏のエピローグ
Epilogue in the Attic
静かに更ける夜に抱かれ
Embraced by the quietly deepening night
空に消える
Disappearing into the sky
白い息 眺めた
I watched the white breath
夢のような時間はいつも
Dream-like time is always
一瞬の
A fleeting
煌めきでも
Sparkle, but still
とても大切なこと
It's something very important
思い出に残して
Keep it in your memories
私を今日(も)温めてくれる
It warms me even today
流れ星に詰め込んだ願い事
Wishes packed into a falling star
また明日 笑顔で会えますように
So that we can meet with a smile again tomorrow
閉じた瞼の裏で輝く
Shining behind closed eyelids
あの景色抱いて 今日は
Embracing that scenery, today...
おやすみ
Good night
待ち遠しい夢の
The continuation
続きを
Of a long-awaited dream
待ちきれない子供みたいに
Like a child who can't wait
下りた幕を背に眺めた星空
The starry sky I watched with the fallen curtain behind my back
明日も輝いていたい
I want to be shining tomorrow too
消えてゆく白熱灯
The incandescent light fading away
眠りゆく街並み
The town falling asleep
愛しい終わりをこの目に映して
Reflecting the lovely ending in these eyes
月明かりの差し込む
Where the moonlight shines in
...眠れぬ夜で
...on sleepless nights,
いくつもの 場面 数え 微笑む
I count so many scenes and smile.
ホログラムで できた夢
A dream made of holograms...
目でも 確かに 触れる 想いで
...with feelings that I can surely see and touch.
だから 流れ星に 詰めた 願い事
So, the wish I put into a shooting star,
また ここで みんなで 歩めますように
is that we can all walk together here again.
繋がってく 夢の途中
In the middle of a connecting dream,
未来への 想いを なんて
holding onto feelings for the future,
おやすみ
goodnight.
重大発表
Major Announcement
サイキョウチックポルカ
Saikyouchic Polka
見逃さないで これが私の流儀
Don't miss it, this is my style!
勘違いされたら そりゃまあやっぱ凹むよ
If I'm misunderstood, well, I'll definitely be down.
君のことが 好きで
Because I love you!
歩み寄って神回避 ちょうどしたかった思い
Stepping closer, a god-tier dodge, the feeling I just wanted to express.
ハート揺れるあの子が どこに居ても目立っちゃう
That girl who makes hearts flutter stands out wherever she is!
サイキョウチックポルカ
Saikyouchic Polka!
21:00 プレミア公開
21:00 Premiere Release
はぁ... はぁ... どこだっけ？ちょっと待って
*pant* *pant* Where was it? Wait a second.
あ、違うな絶対。えーと... つかっ、はぁ...
Ah, that's definitely wrong. Let's see... I mean, *pant*...
あ！はい、もう一回行きます！
Ah! Okay, let's go one more time!
最高！もうステージは始まってんだぜ！あれ？待って。は？はぁー！
Awesome! The stage has already started! Wait, what? Huh? Haaa!
ってサイリウムを、わぁー！って振って分かってくれる？
Can you understand if I wave the glowsticks like, 'Waaa!'?
わぁー！おー、いいね、いいね。お！わぁー！すごいすごいすごい！
Waaa! Oh, nice, nice. Oh! Waaa! Amazing, amazing, amazing!
おお、ポルカより飛んでるよそれ。やばくね？
Whoa, that's flying higher than Polka. Isn't that crazy?
あ、君追っかけるから。だから君わぁー！って走って、ちゃんと、ちゃんとこう行かないとだめだからね
Ah, I'll chase you. So you run like, 'Waaa!', and you have to go properly, okay?
あ、そうそうそうそう。危ないから、その外れたりするとさ、落ちちゃったりすると危ないから
Ah, right, right, right. It's dangerous, if you go off track and fall, it's dangerous.
ちゃんと前見てね、こうやって。前、前、前、大丈夫？あ、あ、ああーっ
Look straight ahead, like this. Front, front, front, you okay? Ah, ah, aaaaah!
チャンネル登録者数100万人 ありがとう!!!
My channel's reached 1 million subscribers! THANK YOU!!!
My channel's reached 1 million subscribers! THANKS!!!
皆様、今回は尾丸ポルカ2周年配信を最後までご覧いただきありがとうございました
Everyone, thank you very much for watching Omaru Polka's 2nd Anniversary stream until the end.
見てくださって誠にありがとうございます。
Thank you very much for watching.
尾丸ポルカです。
I'm Omaru Polka.
ってことで、今回も2周年を記念してグッズを作りました！
And so, I've made goods to celebrate my 2nd anniversary!
何て？
What's that?
へへ、今回も2周年を記念してグッズを作りました。
Hehe, I've made goods to celebrate my 2nd anniversary.
今回もポルカが「まあ良いな」って思ったものを
Once again, I've packed in everything
本当に、本当に詰め込みに詰め込ませていただきました。
that Polka thought was really, really good.
こちらです。どうぞ！
Here they are. Take a look!
だだーん！
Ta-da!
活動2周年フルセットはキャンバスアート、
The 2nd Anniversary Full Set includes canvas art,
ブロマイドセット、おまる座はっぴー！の3点セット！
a bromide set, and an Omaru-za Happi!
2周年公演記念キャンバスアートは、
The 2nd Anniversary Performance Commemorative Canvas Art
クガフーナ先生描き下ろしの素敵なキャンバスアートになっております。
is a wonderful piece drawn by Kuga Fuuna-sensei.
はい次！
Alright, next!
ついに！ついに尾丸ポルカ1st EP『Welcome To POLKA!』が出ます！
Finally! Finally, Omaru Polka's 1st EP 'Welcome To POLKA!' is coming out!
今回の配信で歌った楽曲が詰まりに詰まっております。
It's packed with the songs I sang during this stream.
ついに出せて本当に嬉しいです。
I'm so happy to finally be able to release it.
こちら、皆さん買って部屋に飾ったり聴いていただけるととっても嬉しいです。
I'd be very happy if you bought it, displayed it in your room, or listened to it.
もうジャケットがめちゃくちゃ格好いい。
The jacket art is just so cool.
もう赤くて本当に気持ちが高まるよね。
The red color really gets you excited, doesn't it?
今日歌った歌もほぼほぼ入ってます。
Almost all the songs I sang today are in there.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
次！
Next!
2周年公演記念ブロマイドセットは...あら可愛い。
The 2nd Anniversary Performance Commemorative Bromide Set... oh, how cute.
2Lサイズ127×178ミリメートル。
2L size, 127 x 178 millimeters.
3種のブロマイドがセットになっております。あら可愛い。
It's a set of 3 different bromides. So cute.
どれも魅力的なポルカですね。
They're all such charming shots of Polka.
こちら、おまる座はっぴでハッピー。
And here, the Omaru-za Happi de Happy.
いやこれはね、ポルカ本当にマジデザインにこだわって、
I really put a lot of thought into the design,
ライブとか配信に着てもらいたいし、もう見てもらいたいんだよね。
I want you to wear it to concerts or while watching streams.
すごい、背中がね、あの尻尾とか描いてる。
It's great, the back has my tail and everything drawn on it.
もうだからお揃いなんだよね。もう。
So we'll be matching. Really.
これもね素材がね、すごいいいものにしたくて、
I also wanted the material to be really high quality,
めちゃくちゃ運営さんと一生懸命相談しました。
so I discussed it very thoroughly with the staff.
多分もう君たちが一番着て「あ、いいものだな」っていうものになっております。
I think it's something you'll wear and feel the quality of.
最高！
It's the best!
さらに！2周年フルセットには、なんと！
What's more! The 2nd Anniversary Full Set includes,
尾丸ポルカからの複製手書きお手紙と
a duplicate handwritten letter from Omaru Polka
特典ボイス、二人っきりのアンコールが付いてくる！
and a bonus voice track, 'Encore for Two'!
あ、あ組のね、買ってくれた人にしかもう言えないんだけど、
I can only say this to those in the 'A-gumi' who buy it,
もう手紙とかもめちゃくちゃ心込めて綴ってます。
but I poured my heart into writing that letter.
まあね、これね前回もやったんですけど、すごくご好評につき、
We did this last time too, but it was so well-received,
またねちょっともう1枚分のね、お手紙びっしりドバッて、
that I've filled another whole page with my feelings,
気持ちばっかり込めたので読んでくれると嬉しいです。
so I'd be happy if you'd read it.
買ってね、確かめてくれると嬉しぎ。
I'd be super happy if you'd buy it and check it out.
そして特典ボイスは、二人っきりのアンコールね。
And the bonus voice track is 'Encore for Two'.
なるほど二人っきりのアンコール。二人っきりアンコール、
I see, 'Encore for Two'. Encore for just the two of us...
うーん舞台の、うーん終わりのカーテン裏かな？とかで、
Maybe behind the curtain after the show? Something like that...
うーんまあ分かるやろ！
Well, you get the idea!
なのでぜひぜひフルセットご検討、お買い求めいただけると幸いです。
So please do consider purchasing the full set.
ま、もちろんグッズ単品でもお買い求めいただけますのでご安心を。
Of course, you can also buy the items individually, so don't worry.
詳しくはホロライブ公式ホームページをチェックしてみてください。
Please check the official Hololive homepage for more details.
そして続きまして、楽曲リリース情報です。ドーン！
And moving on, here's some music release news. Boom!
尾丸ポルカオリジナル楽曲3週連続配信第1弾として、
As the 1st of 3 consecutive weekly single releases,
『サイキョウチックポルカ』がこの後0時から配信となります。
'Saikyo-tick Polka' will be available from midnight tonight!
作曲は田中秀和さん、作詞はこだまさおりさんに
I asked Hidekazu Tanaka to compose it and
お願いいたしました。本当にありがとうございます。
Saori Kodama to write the lyrics. Thank you so much.
才脳(才能)の皆はわかるかな。
I'm sure you talented folks know who they are.
ポルカが本当に本当に作ってもらいたかった夢をこちら叶えられました。
A dream of Polka's has really, really come true with this.
この後21時からはこちらもすごく手の込んだMVが公開される予定ですので、
A very elaborate MV is also scheduled for release at 9 PM,
こちらもまた見に来てください。
so please come and watch that too.
そして第2弾となる8月24日、こちらも0時、
Then for the 2nd release on August 24th, also at midnight—
8月23日は24時ですね、から『屋根裏のエピローグ』。
that's midnight on the 23rd—'Yaneura no Epilogue'.
今日歌ったのすごかったやろ。
The performance earlier today was great, wasn't it?
あれも配信されるんで。同日MVも配信されるんで。
That'll be released too. And the MV will be out the same day.
そして第3弾、8月31日0時、8月30日は、
And for the 3rd release on August 31st at midnight—
8月30日は24時かな。はい。
that's midnight on August 30th. Yes.
ようやく『ホログラムサーカス』配信となりました。
Finally, 'Hologram Circus' is being released.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
こちらもぜひチェックしておいてください。
Please be sure to check that out as well.
ポルカからの、えー伝言は以上に、
That's all for the messages from—
ポルだれ(誰)から伝言されてるんですか。
Wait, who's giving the message to Polka?
ポルカからのご案内は以上になります。
That's all the announcements from Polka.
本当に今日は公演に来てくださってありがとうございました。
Thank you so much for coming to today's performance.
お足元の悪い中ね、来てくださって見てくださってありがとうございました。
Thank you for coming and watching, even with the bad weather.
お天気か？
Was it the weather?
天気だったかもしれんな。はい。
Maybe it was just the weather. Yes.
というわけで、来年、再来年と
So, next year and the year after,
またのお越しを心よりお待ちしております。
I look forward to seeing you all again.
舞台「尾丸ポルカ」
～あゝ素晴らしきアイドル人生かな～
Stage Play 'Omaru Polka'
~Ah, What a Wonderful Idol Life~
アイドルに笑顔なんて要らない。
Idols don't need smiles.
そんな世界は要らない。
I don't need a world like that.
あゝ素晴らしきアイドル人生かな
Ah, what a wonderful idol life